A Guide to the American Conservation Association (ACA) records FA475
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Conservation Association (ACA) records
1921, 1928, 1932, 1943-1944, 1952-2010
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Conservation Association
Whyte, William Hollingsworth
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated
FA475
84.58 Cubic Feet 218 letter size document boxes, 1 legal size document box, 2 oversized flat boxes, 1 small artifact box
Related Archival Materials note
Island Resources Foundation records Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. records Laurance S. Rockefeller papers Willam H. Whyte papers
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 15 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents note
The collection primarily consists of grant files, administrative records and financial records.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as received by Rockefeller Archive Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
American Conservation Association deposited the records at the Rockefeller Archive Center in April 1985.
RAC began receiving ACA records in 1990 (Accession 1990:117). Additions and accruals to the collection have been received in multiple accessions, and continue periodically as applicable.
Nature conservation; City planners; Outdoor recreation
- Administrative/Organization, 1958-2008, 2010; 1; 14.44 document box(es) Document boxes 1-38, and part of box 39
  - Board of Trustees, 1959-1960, 1963-1964, 1967, 1969-1971, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, List of Meeting Dates, 1958-1972, 1965, 1967, 1972, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, First Meeting of the Incorporated, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1958 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1959 September 10-11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1960 October 29, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1961 July 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1962 September 20-21, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1963 September 5-6, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1964 October 15, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1965 September 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1966 September 8-9, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1967 September 7 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1968 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1969 September 4 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1970 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1971 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1972 September 7-8 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1973 September 6-7 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1974 September 4-5 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1975 September 4-5 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1976 September 9-10 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1977 October 20-21, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1978 September 22-23, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1979 October 25-26, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1980 October 16-17 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1981 September 10-11, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1982 October 22-23, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1983 September 12-13 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1984 October 22-23, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1985 September 4 (Box 6, Folder 39-40)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1986 October 2-3, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1987 September 2-3 (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1988 October 13 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1989 September 26, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 48-50)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1990 September 6 (Box 8, Folder 51-52)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1991 October 10, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 53-54)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes. 1992 September 1992, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 55-56)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1993 October 21, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1994 September 22, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1995 September 22, 1994-1996 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1996 October 17-18 (Box 10, Folder 60-61)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1997 October 10, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1998 October 7, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 1999 October 5, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2000 October 10 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2001 December 13 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2002 October 11 (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2003 October 31 (Box 12, Folder 69)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2004 December 20 (Box 12, Folder 70)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2005 December 12 (Box 12, Folder 71-72)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2007 December 18 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2008 December 15 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting and Minutes, 2009 December 14 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1963, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 82-83)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 86)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 87-88)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1967, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1968, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 92)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meteing and Minutes, 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 93)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 97)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 99)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 101-102)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1992, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 109-110)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 111)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1994, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 112)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 113)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 114)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 115)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 1998, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and MInutes, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Meeting and Minutes, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Approvals, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 122)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 124)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 125)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 127)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 128)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 135)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 136)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 137)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Memoranda, 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - Board of Trustees, Proposed Meeting, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Board of Trustees Member, Kenneth Chorley, 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 147-148)
  - Alaska II, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 149-150)
  - American Conservation Association, 1958, 1960, 1963-1965, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 151)
  - American Conservation Association, 1958-1963 (Box 21, Folder 152)
  - American Conservation Association, Tax ID Number, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 153)
  - American Conservation Association (ACA), 40th Anniversary, Report, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 154)
  - American Conservation Association (ACA), 40th Anniversary, Photographs, Negatives, etc., 1999 (Box 21, Folder 155)
  - American Conservation Association (ACA), 40th Anniversary, Barrier Islands (Box 21)
  - Annual Report of Treasurer, 1959-1963 (Box 21, Folder 156)
  - Annual Report 1969/Summary Report 1958-1969 (Box 21, Folder 157)
  - Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 158)
  - Annual Reports, Printing and Proof, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 159)
  - Articles, Billboards, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 160)
  - Articles on Tongass National Forest, Alaska, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 161)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Colonial Williamsburg, 1984 October 22-23 (Box 22, Folder 162)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Jackson, Wyoming, 1985 September 4-5, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 163)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Westchester, New York. 1986 October 2-3, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 165)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Jackson, Wyoming, 1987 September 1-4, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 166)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), New York, New York, 1988 October 12-14, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 167)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Adirondacks, New York, 1989 September 25-28, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 168)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Jackson, Wyoming, 1990 September 6-7 (Box 23, Folder 169)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Mohonk, New Paltz, 1991 October 9-11 (Box 23, Folder 170)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Publications, Mohonk, New Paltz, 1991 October 9-11 (Box 23, Folder 171)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Jackson, Wyoming, 1992 September 10-11, 1990-1992 (Box 24, Folder 172)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Woodstock, Vermont, 1993 October 21-22 (Box 24, Folder 173)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), Miscellaneous, 1989-1990, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 174)
  - Board Meetings, American Conservation Association (ACA)/Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI), 2001 (Box 24, Folder 175)
  - Bank Resolution, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 177)
  - Booklet/Brochure, 1966-1970 (Box 24, Folder 178)
  - By-Laws, 1958, 1960, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 180)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 185)
  - Charter, 1958, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 186)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 187)
  - Consultants, 1966-1967, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 188)
  - District of Columbia Licensing and Filing Requirements, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 191)
  - Draper Associates II, Limited Partnership Meeting, 1993 June 25 (Box 25, Folder 192-193)
  - Earth Day International, Loan, 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 194)
  - Employees, 1961, 1966-1967, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 200)
  - Environmental Assessment Council, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 201)
  - Environmental Bond Issues, Hazardous Wastes, etc., 1986, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 202)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of New York, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 204)
  - Finance, 1958, 1960-1968 (Box 25, Folder 205)
  - General Correspondence, A, 1963-1971 (Box 26, Folder 208-209)
  - General Correspondence, B, 1965-1967, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 210)
  - General Correspondence, Holt Bodinson, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 211)
  - General Correspondence, C, 1961, 1963-1971 (Box 26, Folder 212-213)
  - General Correspondence, Chesapeake Bay Foundation, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 214)
  - General Correspondence, D-E, 1963-1971 (Box 27, Folder 215-216)
  - General Correspondence, F, 1962-1964, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 217)
  - General Correspondence, Florida Institute of Technology, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 218)
  - General Correspondence, G, 1965, 1967-1971 (Box 27, Folder 219)
  - General Correspondence, H, 1965-1971, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 220)
  - General Correspondence, I-J, 1966-1970 (Box 27, Folder 221)
  - General Correspondence, K-L, 1963-1964, 1966-1969, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 222)
  - General Correspondence, M (1 of 2), 1961, 1965-1971 (Box 27, Folder 223)
  - General Correspondence, N, 1958, 1961-1964, 1966-1971 (Box 28, Folder 225-226)
  - General Correspondence, O-P, 1964, 1966, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 227)
  - General Correspondence, Q-R, 1964-1965, 1967-1972 (Box 28, Folder 228)
  - General Correspondence, S, 1963, 1967-1971 (Box 29, Folder 229)
  - General Correspondence, T, 1965-1967, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 230)
  - General Correspondence, Ua-United, 1968-1972 (Box 29, Folder 231)
  - General Correspondence, University of Alabama-University of North Carolina, 1966, 1968-1971 (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - General Correspondence, University of Pennsylvania-Utah State College, 1966-1970 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - General Correspondence, V, 1964, 1968-1969, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 234)
  - General Correspondence, Wa-We, 1963, 1966, 1968-1971 (Box 29, Folder 235)
  - General Correspondence, Wh-Z, 1963, 1966, 1968-1971 (Box 30, Folder 236)
  - General Correspondence, Williams College, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 237)
  - General Correspondence, William G. Wing, 1958-1966 (Box 30, Folder 238)
  - Grant Related Chronological File, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 239)
  - Grants to American Conservation Association (ACA) and Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated (JHPI), 1969-1980 (Box 31, Folder 245-246)
  - Hanks, Nancy, Memorial Post Office Project, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 247)
  - Interest in Land Use, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 248)
  - Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated (JHPI), Gifts to American Conservation Association, 1958-1959, 1961, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 249)
  - Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated (JHPI), Meeting of Members and Trustees, 1993 October 22 (Box 31, Folder 250)
  - Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated (JHPI), Working Papers, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 251)
  - Lamb, George R., Correspondence, 1964-1970 (Box 32, Folder 255)
  - Lamb, George R., Keep Rye Beautiful, 1964-1966, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 259)
  - Lamb, George R., Troy Meadows, 1959, 1965, 1968-1969 (Box 33, Folder 260-261)
  - Legal, 1964-1965, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 262)
  - "Man and His Urban Environment", 1972 (Box 33, Folder 264)
  - Maze, Paul, Memorial Book, 1984-1985 (Box 33, Folder 265)
  - Morgan, A. K., Trip for American Conservation Association (ACA), Interstate Park at Lake Tahoe, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 269)
  - Office Equipment, 1964-1965 (Box 33, Folder 270)
  - Office Matters, 1958, 1960, 1965-1966, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 271)
  - Office Space, Lease, 1960, 1963-1971 (Box 33, Folder 273)
  - Office Space, State Council of Parks Office Space, 1963-1964 (Box 34, Folder 275)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission, Robert O. Binnewies, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 277)
  - Pennies for the Planet, re: Trees, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 279)
  - Plan and Purpose, 1960-1961, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 280)
  - The President-Elect's Task Force on the Environment, Ronald Reagan, 19881 (Box 34, Folder 281)
  - Press Releases, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 282)
  - Report, Why the Jackson Hole Airport Needs to Be Replaced, 1975, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 283)
  - Reports Employer, Management Improper Practices Act, 1960-1961, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 284)
  - Reports New York (State of) Department of Labor, New York Minimum Wage Act, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 285)
  - Review and Planning Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 36, Folder 299)
  - Rockefeller, Larry, Parks Project, 1994-1996 (Box 36, Folder 301)
  - Rockefeller, Larry, Trip to Colorado and Costa Rica, 1995 March 18-April 3, 1994-1995 (Box 36, Folder 302)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance, Guidelines and Study of American Conservation Association (ACA) and Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc.'s (JHPI) Programs and Policies, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 303)
  - Rungius, Carl, Paintings, Correspondence, 1977-1978, 1982-1983, 1985-1986, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 305-306)
  - Rungius, Carl, Paintings, 1977-1978, 1990-1993 (Box 37, Folder 307)
  - Rungius, Carl, Paintings, 1986, 1990-1995, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 308-309)
  - Rungius, Carl, Paintings, 1984, 1990, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 310-311)
  - Smith, M. Frederik, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 313)
  - Smith, M. Frederik, Addresses, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 314)
  - Special Fund, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 316)
  - Subscriptions and Book Purchases, 1963-1971 (Box 38, Folder 319)
  - Taxes, 1958-1964, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 321)
  - Wirth Medal, Wirth Environmental Award, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 325)
  - World Monuments Fund, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 326)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), Annual Reports, 1967-1969, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 327)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), Annual Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 328)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), The Electric Utility Industry and the Environment, Publication, etc., 1968 (Box 39, Folder 329)
  - Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality (CACEQ), Publications, 1972-1976 (Box 39, Folder 330-331)
  - Man and His Urban Environment, Publication and Press Materials, 1972-1973, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 333)
- Grant Files, 1921, 1928, 1932, 1938, 1943, 1952, 1955-2009; 2; 53.68 box(es) Boxes 39-180, 1 small artifact box
  - Declinations, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 336)
  - A-Af, 1972, 1974, 1976-1980, 1982, 1984-1986, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 339)
  - Al, 1977-1978, 1980-1981, 1983, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 340)
  - Am, 1975, 1977-1981, 1983, 1985-1986, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 341-342)
  - An-Ar, 1974, 1976-1981, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 343)
  - As-Au, 1975, 1977-1978,1999 (Box 41, Folder 344)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences, 1986-1987, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 345-346)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1981, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 347)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1980, 1986-1991 (Box 41, Folder 348-350)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1990-1993 (Box 42, Folder 354-355)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1992-1995 (Box 43, Folder 356-357)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 358)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1996-1997 (Box 43, Folder 359)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1997-1998 (Box 43, Folder 360)
  - The Adirondack Council, 1998-2000 (Box 43, Folder 362)
  - The Adirondack Council, 2000-2001 (Box 43, Folder 363)
  - The Adirondack Council, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 364)
  - The Adirondack Council, Acid Rain, 1986-1987 (Box 43, Folder 365)
  - Adirondack Land Trust, Incorporated, 1984-1986 (Box 43, Folder 366)
  - Adirondack Land Trust, Incorporated, 1986-1988, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 367-368)
  - Adirondack Mountain National Park (Proposed), 1968 (Box 43, Folder 369)
  - Adirondack Nature Conservancy, 1988-1991 (Box 43, Folder 370)
  - Adirondack Nature Conservancy and Adirondack Land Trust, Incorporated, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 371)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1987-1991 (Box 44, Folder 373)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1991-1995 (Box 44, Folder 374)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 375)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 44, Folder 376)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 44, Folder 378)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 44, Folder 380)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 44, Folder 381)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2001-2002 (Box 44, Folder 382)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2001-2003 (Box 44, Folder 383)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2001, 2003-2004 (Box 44, Folder 384)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box 44, Folder 385)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 44, Folder 386)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2006-2007 (Box 44, Folder 387)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2007-2008 (Box 44, Folder 388)
  - Alaska Conservation Foundation, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 389)
  - Alaska Fund for the Future, 1996-1997 (Box 44, Folder 390)
  - Alaska Fund for the Future, 1997-1998 (Box 44, Folder 391)
  - Alaska Fund for the Future, 1998-2000 (Box 45, Folder 393)
  - Alaska Project, 1998-1999 (Box 45, Folder 394)
  - Alaska (State of) Recreation and Tourist Potential Plan, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 395)
  - Alaska Wilderness League, 2006 (Box 45, Folder 396)
  - Alaskan Conservation Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box 45, Folder 397)
  - American Association of State and Local History, 1964, 1970, 1975-1977 (Box 45, Folder 398)